Guide to the Secular Yiddish Schools in North America Collection M0732
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Yiddish school files
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Becker, Patty
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    Photographs taken during interview. Patty Becker is graduate of AR shuln, Detroit. Color, 1994.
    Photographs.; Becker, Patty
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    Letter of thanks for participating in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish, 1994.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Benyas, Shirley (Sarah)
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    Photographs taken during interview. Shirley Benyas is a graduate of Farband shuln and SA Mitlshul, Detroit.
    Photographs.; Benyas, Shirley (Sarah)
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Borovik, Leyb
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    Photographs taken during interview. Color, 1993.
    Photographs.; Borovik, Leyb
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish, 1992.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Chaikin, Bernice B.
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    Photographs taken during interview. Color, 1992.
    Photographs.; Chaikin, Bernice B.
  - Correspondence, 1995; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    Letter of thanks for participating in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish, 1995.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Cymerman, Hadassah
  - Photographs, 1995; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    Photographs taking during interview. Color, ca. 1995.
    Photographs.; Cymerman, Hadassah
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    Letter of thanks for participating in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish, 1992.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Dorn, Miriam Zelchin
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    Photographs taken during interview. Color, ca. 1992.
    Photographs.; Dorn, Miriam Zelchin
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish, 1993.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Drachler, Nachman
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 18)
    Photographs.; Drachler, Nachman
  - Correspondence, 1995; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project. Copy, in Yiddish, 1995.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Foner, Henry and Lorraine
  - Photographs, 1995; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    Photographs taken during interview. Color, 1995.
    Photographs.; Foner, Henry and Lorraine
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Getzoff, Martha
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    Photographs.; Getzoff, Martha
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 23)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Goldberg, Itche
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 24)
    Photographs taken during interview. Color, 1993
    Photographs.; Goldberg, Itche
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 25)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Goldstein, Sima
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 26)
    Photographs.; Goldstein, Sima
  - Correspondence, 1995; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 27)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Goodman, Eli
  - Photographs, 1995; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 28)
    Color photographs taken during interview, ca. 1995.
    Photographs.; Goodman, Eli
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 29)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1992.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Greenspan, Rose Schulman
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 30)
    Color photographs taken during interview, 1992.
    Photographs.; Greenspan, Rose Schulman
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 31)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1994.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Grossberg, Peretz
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 32)
    Color photographs taken during interview, 1994.
    Photographs.; Grossberg, Peretz
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 33)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Hartman, Hershl
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 34)
    Photographs.; Hartman, Hershl
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 35)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Harwood, Naomi Bitner
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 36)
    Color photographs taken during interview, 1994. (Farband Shuln, Detroit.)
    Photographs.; Harwood, Naomi Bitner
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 37)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1992. Kahn attended Yiddish schools in Winnipeg, Canada; was Yiddish teacher and activist.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Kahn, Taybl.
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 38)
    Photographs.; Kahn, Taybl.
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 39)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Kaufman, Rakhmiel
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 40)
    Photographs.; Kaufman, Rakhmiel
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 41)
    Letter of thanks for participating in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1992.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Kiel, Khonen
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 42)
    Photographs.; Kiel, Khonen
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 43)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Klein, Mendl Dovid
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 44)
    Photographs.; Klein, Mendl Dovid
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 45)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1993.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Kornfeld, Gita
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 46)
    Color photographs taken during interview, 1993.
    Photographs.; Kornfeld, Gita
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 47)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Krow-Lucal, Martha G.
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 48)
    Photographs.; Krow-Lucal, Martha G.
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 49)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Krupit, Perl
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 72, Folder 50)
    Photographs.; Krupit, Perl
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1994. Kryshtal taught in NY AR Shuln.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Kryshtal, Khane
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    Photographs.; Kryshtal, Khane
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, 1992, copy, in Yiddish.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Laks, Leye
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    Photographs.; Laks, Leye
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Levine, Chane
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    Photographs.; Levine, Chane
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Levine, Merke
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    Color photographs taken during interviews, 1993.
    Photographs.; Levine, Merke
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Macovski, Al
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    Photographs.; Macovski, Al
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    Letter of thanks for participating in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1994.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Margolis, Chassie
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    Photographs.; Margolis, Chassie
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Menkin, Eudice Feder
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    Color photographs taken during interview, ca. 1992.
    Photographs.; Menkin, Eudice Feder
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1994. Ovshinsky was AR student in Akron, OH and AR aktiver tuer (leader) in AR Shuln, Detroit.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Ovshinsky, Herb
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 16)
    Photographs.; Ovshinsky, Herb
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Salotaroff, Reeva
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    Photographs.; Salotaroff, Reeva
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 19)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Schlosser, Nekhe Shmulevitsh
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    Photographs.; Schlosser, Nekhe Shmulevitsh
  - Correspondence, 1991; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1991.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Shak, Gella Messinger
  - Photographs, 1991; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 22)
    Color photographs taken during interview, 1991.
    Photographs.; Shak, Gella Messinger
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 23)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Shaw, Malke Yaffe
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 24)
    Photographs.; Shaw, Malke Yaffe
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 25)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Sumpf, Clara
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 26)
    Color photographs taken during interview, ca 1993.
    Photographs.; Sumpf, Clara
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 27)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Wanamaker, Edith/Bashe
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 28)
    Photographs.; Wanamaker, Edith/Bashe
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 29)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Woll, Alice
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 30)
    Photographs.; Woll, Alice
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 31)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Breitrose, Henry S.
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 32)
    Photographs.; Breitrose, Henry S.
  - Interview transcription, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 33)
    Interview transcription, 1993.
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Breitrose, Henry S.
  - Correspondence, 1995; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 34)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, 1995.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Davidson, Esther Borenstein
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 35)
    Photographs.; Davidson, Esther Borenstein
  - Interview transcription, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 36)
    Interview transcription, 1994.
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Davidson, Esther Borenstein
  - Correspondence, 1996; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 37)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, 1996. Fifer was student in SA Shule 15, Brooklyn, NY.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Fifer, Donald (Doni)
  - Photographs, 1996; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 38)
    Color photographs taken during interview, 1996.
    Photographs.; Fifer, Donald (Doni)
  - Interview transcription, 1996; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 39)
    Interview transcription, 1996.
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Fifer, Donald (Doni)
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 40)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Fogel, Alfie (Efrayim)
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 41)
    Color photographs sent during interview, 1994.
    Photographs.; Fogel, Alfie (Efrayim)
  - Interview transcription, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 43)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Fisher, Morris
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 73, Folder 44)
    Photographs.; Fisher, Morris
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1994. Farband Shuln, Detroit.
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Interview transcription, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Greenberg, Deena Goldsmith
  - Correspondence, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, 1994.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Friedman, Sarah
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    Color photographs taken during interview, 1994. Friedman was boyer-farvalter kultur tuer, SA Institute, Detroit.
  - Interview transcription, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Friedman, Sarah
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Katz, Eli
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    Photographs.; Katz, Eli
  - Interview transcription, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    Interview transcription, 1993
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Katz, Eli
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, 1993.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Kugler, Israel
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    Photographs taken during interview, 1993.
    Photographs.; Kugler, Israel
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Interview transcription, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Kugler, Israel
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Majsner, Lilke
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    Photographs.; Majsner, Lilke
  - Interview transcription, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    Interview transcription, 1992.
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Majsner, Lilke
  - Correspondence, 1995; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, copy, in Yiddish, 1995.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Mark, Harry (Hershl)
  - Photographs, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    Color photographs taken during interview, ca. 1994.
    Photographs.; Mark, Harry (Hershl)
  - Interview transcription, 1994; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Mark, Harry (Hershl)
  - Correspondence, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Olitzky, Mattis
  - Photographs, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    Photographs.; Olitzky, Mattis
  - Interview transcription, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 21)
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Olitzky, Mattis
  - Photographs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 22)
    Color photographs taken during interview, undated.
    Photographs.; Toren, David
  - Correspondence, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 23)
    Letter of thanks for participation in oral history project, original, in Yiddish, 1992.
    Correspondence: SYSA Collection and Oral History Project; Weissman, Sylvia Dobzinsky
  - Photographs, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 24)
    Photographs.; Weissman, Sylvia Dobzinsky
  - Interview transcription, 1992; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 25)
    Interview transcription, 1992. Weissman attended SA Shule 14, Brooklyn, NY.
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity; Weissman, Sylvia Dobzinsky
  - Interviews, 1993; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 74, Folder 26)
    Four 3-1/2" floppy disks, ca. 1993, containing transcription files of interviews by Gella Schweid Fishman with Borenstein-Davidson, Olitzky, Mark, Eli Katz, Perl Krupit, Sarah Friedman.
    Oral History Project: Tapes, Transcriptions, Outreach/ Publicity
  - Photographs, 1990s; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    Interview photographs of unidentified woman, color, ca. 1990s.
  - Photographs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    BandW photographs, ca. 1940s and 1950s.
  - Photographs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    BandW photographs, ca. 1940s and 1950s, Kings Highway Shule.
  - Photographs, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    BandW photographs, ca. 1940s-1970s.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    Kinder Zhurnal: Apr-May 1922; Apr. 1925; Nov 1931; Apr 1932; Aug-Sept 1935; Jun-Jul 1936. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    Kinder Zhurnal: Feb, Mar, Apr, Oct, Nov 1935. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    Kinder Zhurnal: Jan, Mar, Apr 1938; Oct 1939. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    Kinder Zhurnal: Mar, Aug-Sept 1945; Mar, Nov 1946; Oct, Nov 1951; Jan, Oct 1954; Jan 1955. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    Kinder Zhurnal: Jan, Dec 1955; Feb, Dec 1956; Mar, Dec 1957. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    Kinder Zhurnal: Jan, Mar, Oct, Dec 1958; Feb, Oct 1959. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    Kinder Zhurnal: Mar 1960; Jan, Dec 1963; Feb, Apr 1964; Jan 1965. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    Kinder Zhurnal: Jan 1966; Feb, Mar, Oct 1967; Dec 1968. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder zhurnal, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    Kinder Zhurnal: May 1971; Win 1973; Spr, Sum, Fall 1974; Apr 1976. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    Kinder tseytung: Mar 1937. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1954-1955. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1956. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1957-1959. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1960-1962. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1964. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1966. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1967-1968. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1970. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1976-1979. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Kinder tseytung, Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    Kinder tseytung: various issues 1981-1982. Originals, in Yiddish.
  - Videnkol, 1937; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    Videnkol, vol. 1, no. 1, 1937. Original, in Yiddish.
  - Serials, 1935-1936; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    [SA Folk Institut] Buletin, no. 1-3; 6-8, 1935-1936.
  - Serials, 1936-1937; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    [SA Folk Institut] Buletin, no. 9-12, 1936-1937.
  - Serials, 1938; 1941; Accession no. 2003-318 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    [SA Folk Institut] Buletin, no. 13-15, 1938; 1941.
  - Der Ilpik, Accession no. 2003-318; 1941-1944 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    Der Ilpik, published by the Y.L. Perets Yugnt Klub. Jan-Jun, 1941.
    Publications for Children; Fishman, Joshua A. (Shikl)
  - Der Ilpik, Accession no. 2003-318; 1941-1944 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    Der Ilpik, published by the Y.L. Perets Yugnt Klub. Nov, Dec 1941.
  - Der Ilpik, Accession no. 2003-318; 1941-1944 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    Der Ilpik, published by the Y.L. Perets Yugnt Klub. Oct., 1942.
  - Der Ilpik, Accession no. 2003-318; 1941-1944 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    Der Ilpik, published by the Y.L. Perets Yugnt Klub. Jan-Apr, 1942.
  - Der Ilpik, Accession no. 2003-318; 1941-1944 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    Der Ilpik, published by the Y.L. Perets Yugnt Klub. Sof Apr, 1942.
  - Der Ilpik, Accession no. 2003-318; 1941-1944 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    Der Ilpik, published by the Y.L. Perets Yugnt Klub. Jun, 1942.
  - Der Ilpik, Accession no. 2003-318; 1941-1944 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    Der Ilpik, published by the Y.L. Perets Yugnt Klub. Jan, 1943.